Guide to the Records of the North American Jewish Students Appeal, undated, 1962, 1964-1996 (bulk 1971-1995) *I-338 and *I-338A
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series III: Constituent Files, undated, 1962, 1964-1995 (bulk 1971-1995); Boxes 35-51.
  The subseries regarding Constituents follow the same general pattern, with materials specifically associated with the Constituent included. The pattern contains files on Constituent activities, allocations received, clippings, correspondence, financial statements, memos addressed to the specific Constituent, quarterly reports, and constitutions, by-laws and/or articles of incorporation. The series was created by pulling the yearly records of the Constituents from the general records, which were originally (but inconsistently) filed by program year, depending on who served as Executive Director in a given period. Since the Constituents stood on their own as separate entities under the NAJSA, it was decided to pull all files and documents regarding the Constituents from the original pattern of the collection and file them together. In rearranging the documents in this way, each Constituent could be regarded on its own merit and researched accordingly. However, the materials included for the Constituents do not act as a primary collection. Each of the following Constituent subseries serves as a snapshot of each Constituent, not as a complete record. For related collections within the American Jewish Historical Society regarding certain Constituents, please see Related Materials.
  Originally Constituent files consisted of certain materials filed under 'Activities,' 'Maps,' and 'Updates.' These files served the purpose of informing the APPEAL of each Constituent's activities for any given period for inclusion in reports written to national and local federations, plus various other fundraising devices. 'Activities' folders sent by the Constituent outlined specific activities of the Constituent. 'Updates' were listed activities by month and very similar in nature to 'Activities' reports. 'Maps' of the United States and Canada were handed in by each Constituent showing where activities were held or outreach conducted in the form of mailings or events throughout North America. Due to the overlapping nature of these items, they have been collectively filed under 'Activities,' by decade. Also, this section is inconsistent as 'Maps' were only used during the latter years of the 1970s and the Constituents were inconsistent in recording and sending reports to the APPEAL regarding activities conducted.
  - Subseries 1: General Records, undated, 1968, 1970-1995; Box 35-37 (Folders 1-11).
    The General Records of the Constituents contains materials concerning the Constituents as a group, including their combined allocation presentations to the NAJSA for the Federations, group memos, allocation 'fair share' formulas and funds distribution votes; miscellaneous budget and financial records, biographies and a joint symposium held by JSPS and RESPONSE in 1991. One folder is dedicated to a dispute between JSPS and NETWORK (Box 36, Folder 14). Two additional Constituents are also included in the General Records, the Progressive Zionist Caucus' Bayit Project, and Lights in Action (LIA). Other material includes applications from organizations wishing to become Constituents of the APPEAL, including the National Jewish Law Students Network, the World Union of Jewish Students, North American Division, and Yavneh Olami, a program devoted to a world network of Jewish religious students. Finally, Box 36, Folder 9 "Coalition and Hillel Meeting, 1995," provides documentation on a meeting between a delegation of Constituent Governing Board members and Hillel to determine the future direction of the funding of the two groups by Federations.
    - Activities-All Constituents, undated, [1981], 1985 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Allocations, 1976-1979 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Allocation Distribution Votes, 1980-1986 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Allocation "Fair Share" Formulas, [1973], [1986], [1988-1989] (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Allocation Form Templates, 1980s (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Allocation Presentations with Quarterly Reports, 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Allocation Presentations, 1989 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Allocation Presentations, 1990 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Allocation Presentations, 1991 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Allocation Presentations, 1992 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Allocation Presentations, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Allocation Presentations, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Allocation Review Procedures, [1980], 1990-1994 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Bayit Project Allocations, Budget and Internal Revenue Correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Bayit Project Articles of Incorporation and By-Laws, undated, 1983, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Bayit Project "Bayit-You'll Like It!' Conference, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Bayit Project Brochures and Mailings, undated, [1984, 1990] (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Bayit Project Clippings, undated, 1985, 1987 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Bayit Project Correspondence, 1980, 1985, 1987-1989 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Bayit Project Information and Operations Manual, undated, 1984-1985, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Bayit Project Notes and Articles, Miscelleneous, undated, [1985] (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Budgets-Proposed, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Coalition and Hillel Meeting, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Constituent Biographies, 1971-[1974] (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Constituent Information, Federation Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Constituent Information, 1993-1995 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Financial Records, 1970-1972 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - JSPS/NETWORK Dispute Correspondence, 1989 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Lights in Action (LIA) Allocations, 1993-1995 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Lights in Action (LIA) Clipping, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Lights in Action (LIA) Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Lights in Action (LIA) Flyers and Mailings, undated, 1993, [1994-1995] (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Lights in Action (LIA) Israel Sourcebook and Haggadah, undated, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Memos-All Constituents, undated, 1972-1977 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Memos-All Constituents, undated, 1978-1984 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Memos-All Constituents, undated, 1985-1992 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - "Multiculturalism, Jews, and the Campus," JSPS/RESPONSE Symposium, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - National Jewish Law Students Network (Jordan Horvath) Constituent Application and Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - News Update, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Pending Constituent Status Organizations, 1968, 1971-1972 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Student Contacts, undated, [1993-1994] (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - World Union of Jewish Students (WUJS) North America Constituent Documentation, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Yavneh Olami (World Organization of Religious Students and B'nei Yeshivot) Correspondence and Flyers, undated, 1989-1990 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 2: Jewish Students Press Service (JSPS), undated, 1971-1995; Box 37 (Folder 12) - 40.
    In addition to following the general pattern of Constituent records, information on JSPS' national and New York editor's conferences, plus additional information on JSPS and RESPONSE's multiculturalism symposium may be found in Subseries 2. During the early 1990s, a dispute between JSPS and the NAJSA led to accusations of monetary mismanagement on the part of both groups. Documentation of this dispute may be found in Box 38, Folder 13 and Box 39, Folder 1. Other material includes funding proposals, a reorganization draft, and a pledge proposal from a private donor. Correspondence concerning the creation of JSPS' current publication,New Voices, which began in 1991, can be found in Box 38, Folder 12. Editions of the newspaper may be found in Series VII: Publications and Printed Matter,Subseries 1: Constituents, Newspaper Format,New Voices.
    - Activities, undated, 1974-1982 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Activities, 1983-1987, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Allocations, 1970s (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Allocations, 1980s (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Allocations, 1990-1995 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Allocation Requests, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Annual Report, 1973-1975 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Berman (Herbert) Pledge Proposal, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Budget, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Clippings, undated, 1971, 1972, 1978, 1981, 1987, [1992?] (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Deposit Investigation-Allocations and Subscriptions, 1991-1993 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Deposit Investigation-Bank Statements and Checks, 1991-1994 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Editors and Publications List, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Financial Statements, 1975-1977 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Financial Statements, 1978-1979 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Financial Statements, 1980-1983 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Financial Statements, 1984-1987 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Flyers, undated, [1974], 1993 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Funding Proposals, 1990, 1993 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Funding Proposals, 1994-1995 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Internal Revenue Service Correspondence, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Memos, 1976-1982 (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Memos, 1983-1986 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Memos, 1987-1989 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Minutes, June 3-5, 1973; April 24, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Multiculturalism, Jews and The Campus: A Symposium, 1991 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - National Editor's Conference, 1976-1977, 1981-1982, 1984, 1988, 1990 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - New York Area Editor's Conference, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Overdue Rent Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Press Releases, undated, 1978, 1982, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Press Releases-Other Organizations, undated, 1993 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Reorganization Draft Reports, [1987] (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Student Editors Seminar, Israel, 1976, 1981 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1970s (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1980s (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 3: North American Jewish Students' Network (NETWORK), undated, 1971-1986, 1989; Box 41 - Box 43 (Folders 1-9).
    In addition to the pattern of materials found in this subseries, there are documents concerning the New Jewish Media Project(also a grant beneficiary), materials on regional conferences and conventions by NETWORK, a pamphlet entitled "What is NETWORK?", containing a brief history of the group, and materials concerning non-compliance violations and grievance issues between the NAJSA and NETWORK. After a series of incidents that violated NAJSA By-Laws, NETWORK withdrew from the APPEAL in 1985. Information concerning this dispute and its subsequent resolution are located in Box 42, Folders 10-12 and Box 43, Folder 1.
    - Accountant Statements, 1979-1980 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Activities, 1971-1979 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Activities, 1980-1984 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Allocations, 1976-1983 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Alternatives in Jewish Education Conference, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Annual Reports, 1973-1975 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Brochures and Flyers, undated, 1981, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - By-Laws, Certificate of Incorporation, Constitution and Resolutions, 1970s-1980s (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Clippings, 1970s-1980s (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Conventions, 1972, 1975, 1977-1979, 1981, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, n.d, 1971-1979 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1986, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Financial Statements, 1975-1982 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Funding Proposal, 1971-1972 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Internal Revenue Correspondence, 1971 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Memos, undated, 1971, 1976-1980 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Memos, 1981-1983 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Minutes, November 29, 1970 and January 13-14, 1973 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - New Jewish Media Proposal, [1975] (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Non-Compliance Motion Documents, 1979-1982 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Non-Compliance Motion Financial Penalty Documents, 1984-1985 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Non-Compliance Motion Memoranda of Agreement, 1978-1979 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Non-Compliance Motion Monies Owed to NAJSA Correspondence and Notes, 1979-1982 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Overdue Rent and Floor Plan Correspondence and Memos, 1980-1981 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Press Kit, 1983 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Press Releases, undated, 1978, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Program Proposals, 1974-1976, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Regional Conferences and Leadership Development Seminars, 1973-1976, 1980-1981 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1970s (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1980-1982 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - "What is Network?: The History and Activities of the North American Jewish Students' Network", [1975] (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 4: Progressive Zionist Caucus (PZC), undated, 1986-1995; Box 43 (Folders 10-12) - Box 45 (Folders 1-4).
    The records regarding the Progressive Zionist Caucus follow the pattern of materials found in this Series. Additional materials include PZC Governing Board (known as Mazkirut) minutes and agendas, grant proposals, and PZC's constituent application and review materials.
    - Activities, 1980s (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Activities, 1990s (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Allocations, 1987-1995 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Allocation Requests, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Atlanta/Georgia Regional Coordinator Correspondence, undated, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Board (Mazkirut) Agendas and Minutes, undated, 1988, 1991, 1993-1994 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Brochures, undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - By-Laws, Certificate of Incorporation and Constitution, undated, 1981-1989 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, undated, 1986-1988, 1990-1994 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Constituent Status Membership Review, undated, 1986-1987, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1990s (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Director Applications, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Flyers, undated, 1980s-1990s (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Foundation Proposals, undated, 1989-1990 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Grant Proposals and Correspondence, undated, 1985, 1987, 1989, 1991-1992 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Internal Revenue Service Correspondence, 1993 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Program Reports for LCBC Narratives and Grants, 1990-1991 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Quarterly Report, January-March 1987 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Subseries 5:Response: A Contemporary Jewish Review(Jewish Educational Services, Inc.) (RESPONSE), undated, 1970-1995; Box 45 (Folders 5-11) - Box 46 (Folders 1-15).
    The materials in this subseries closely follow the pattern of materials found within this Series. Other than the standard materials, there is one file of correspondence that outlines the financial crisis of the organization (an on-going battle) located in Box 46, Folder 5. The collection contains only one copy of the publication Response: A Contemporary Jewish Review in Box 99, Folder 12. However, the American Jewish Historical Society houses a collecton of the journals.
    - Activities, 1975-1976, 1979 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Activities, undated, [1982-1984], 1988 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Allocations, 1970s (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Allocations, 1980s (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Allocations, 1990s (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Allocation Presentations, 1990, 1993-1994 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - By-Laws and Incorporation, 1970, 1978, 1987-1989 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - By-Laws and Incorporation, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - By-Laws and Incorporation, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1971-1974 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1983-1991 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Financial Situation Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Financial Statements, 1971, 1974-1979 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Financial Statements, 1980-1985, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Internal Revenue Service Correspondence, 1991, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - LCBC Budgets and Partial Narrative, 1987, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Memos, undated, 1976-1991 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Minutes, 1970-1972 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - NAJSA Advertisement, [1975-1976] (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Program Proposals, 1992-1995 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1975-1979 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1980s (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Subseries 6: Student Struggle for Soviet Jewry (with the Center for Russian Jewry) (SSSJ), undated, 1967, 1971-1991; Box 46 (Folder 16) - Box 49 (Folders 1-3).
    The Constituent records regarding SSSJ contain several areas of note besides the records that follow the pattern of the Series. The Flyers and Mailings (Box 48, Folders 1-3) along with the SSSJ's Press Releases (Box 48, Folders 8-12) give detail to the overall activities of this group more fully than the other Constituents in Series III. In addition, the subseries contains testimony by Jacob Birnbaum, a Founder of SSSJ, appearing before the U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Ways and Means concerning Jewish immigration policy in Romania. Also of note are issues of SSSJ's publication The New Heroes, Books I-III, a printed collection of photographs of individuals and families attempting to immigrate from the Soviet Union; the October-November 1978 issue of Freedom!, and a small collection of the Soviet Jewry Action Newsletter. SSSJ was the most vocal and respected of the APPEAL Constituents, and the materials reflect the dynamism behind SSSJ's actions on behalf of Soviet Jewry. Ephemera and posters from this subseries may be found in Series VIII,Subseries 1: Ephemera and Subseries 2: Posters, and correspondence from Susan Dessel to two pen-pal families sponsored from SSSJ, the Partispayan Family (Box 25, Folder 12) and the Reinberg Family (Box 26, Folder 8).
    - Activities, 1967, 1971-1978 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Activities, 1978-1985 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Activities, 1986-1990 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Allocations, 1970s (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Allocations, 1980s (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Banking Documents, 1991 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Birnbaum, Jacob U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Ways and Means Statement Re: Romanian Immigration Policy, June 15, 1978 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Brochures and Postcards, undated, [1970s] (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Budgets and Proposed Budgets, 1970s (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Clippings, undated, 1970-1979 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Clippings, undated, 1980-1990 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1979 (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Financial Reports, 1971-1976 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Financial Reports, 1977-1979 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Financial Statements, 1979-1985 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Financial Statements, 1986-1987 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Freedom!, October-November, 1978 (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Flyers and Mailings, undated, [1970s] (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Flyers and Mailings, undated, [1980s] (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Flyers and Mailings, undated, [1990s] (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Internal Revenue Service Correspondence, 1967 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Materials and Services Available List, undated, [1971-1973] (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Memos, 1978-1991 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - "New Heroes, The," Books I- III, 1974, 1976 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Press Releases, undated, 1975-1979 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Press Releases, 1981-1984, 1986 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Press Releases, 1987 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Press Releases, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Press Releases, 1989-1991 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Press Release Narratives, undated, [1978, 1984, 1987-1989] (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Program Reports, 1972, 1990-1991 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1973-1979 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1980s (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Soviet Jewry Action Newsletter, June 1971; Rosh Hashanah 1976; April 27, 1976, 1977 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Subscriptions, 1990 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 7: Yavneh Religious Students Organization (YAVNEH), undated, 1962, 1964, 1971-1981; Box 49, Folders 4-23.
    YAVNEH withdrew from the APPEAL in January 1978 due to financial difficulties and a somewhat stormy relationship with the APPEAL. The material within this subseries documents some of YAVNEH's activities, but mostly provides information regarding its relationship with the NAJSA. The subseries also includes the program from YAVNEH's 17thannual convention in 1976, and a publication entitled "The Purim Peace" (Box 49, Folders 18 and 21, respectively). One copy of YAVNEH's publication of Dispatch and several copies of Kol Yavneh: The Official Publication of Yavneh can be found in Box 99, Folder 13.
    - Activities, undated, 1973-1977 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Activities, 1979-1981 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Allocations, 1970s-1980s (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Articles of Incorporation, 1962 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Brochures, undated, 1979-1981 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Budgets and Proposed Budgets, 1970s (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, undated, 1971-1979 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Executive Board, 1971-1974, 1979-1980 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Financial Reports, 1973-1980 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Flyers, undated, 1979-1980 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Governing Board Minutes (NAJSA) Regarding Yavneh, September 14, 1976, 1977, 1979 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Internal Revenue Correspondence, 1964 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Memos, 1976-1981 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Narratives, undated (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - National Labor Day Convention, 17thAnnual, Program, September 2-6, 1976 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Newsletters, 1972, 1976 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Press Releases, undated, 1979 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - "Purim Peace, The", [1979-1980] (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Quarterly Reports, 1975-1980 (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - Tear Sheet, 1979 (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - Subseries 8: Yugntruf: Youth for Yiddish (YUGNTRUF), undated, 1965-1966, 1971-1995; Box 50-51.
    Arranged by alphabetical order.
    Yugntruf: Youth for Yiddish, was the second oldest (after SSSJ) established Constituent organization of the NAJSA. Founded in 1965, the organization's aim was to promote and present the Yiddish language, literature, and culture to Yiddish speakers and those learning the language. YUGNTRUF published (and continues to publish) a journal by the same name, filled with new literature on the cultural and political works of Yiddishkeits. This subseries documents YUGNTRUF's relationship with the NAJSA and contains some specialized work on the part of YUGNTRUF's promotion of Yiddish, including one issue of the Bilingual Family Newsletter, flyers and mailings in English and Yiddish, and several Yiddish/English Political Terminology Vocabulary Guides (Box 51, Folder 12). The remainder of the files in this Subseries follows the general pattern of records found in the Series. In addition, the collection holds a good quantity of YUGNTRUF journals, located in Series VII: Publications and Printed Matter, Subseries 1: NAJSA and Constituents,Box 100.
    - Activities, undated, 1971-1979 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Activities, 1980-1989 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Activities, 1990-1994 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Allocations, 1976-1979 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Allocations, 1980-1988 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Allocations, 1989-1995 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Allocations Review, 1990-1994 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Bilingual Family Newsletter, Special Issue on Yiddish, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 8)